amiraliamhh@gmail.com

in <u>linkedin://amiraliameri</u>

o github://amiraliamhh

🖹 stackoverflow://amirali-ameri

Senior full-stack web developer with over 4 years of experience in developing enterprise applications. Expert in **Javascript**, **React**, **Vue.js** and **Node.js**; focused on the entire pipeline of delivering a product, from taking an initial concept to deployment; full-time learner with a fundamental awareness of data structures and algorithms. Specialized in developing SPA and PWA.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Full-Stack Developer

Legamart - 2020-10 / present (2 months) - contract

- Used React, React hooks, CSS-in-JS solutions and Typescript to develop responsive user interfaces for Payment, Availability Service and Case-Review Service of Legamart.
- Worked with Product and UI/UX teams to develop Case-Review microservice of Legamart.

Front-End Tech Lead

Jabama - 2020-05 / present (8 months) - full-time

- Leading a team of 4 to develop the front-end of the redesigned Jabama website.
- Contributed in developing the redesigned version of Jabama PWA.
- Contributed in developing the Admin Panel of Jabama website.
- Worked closely with Marketing and SEO teams and refactored the Jabama website to get higher traffic from search engines.

Full-Stack Developer

Jabama - 2019-09 / 2020-05 (9 months) - full-time

- Contributed to developing the back-end of the search system of Jabama using Node.js, Nest.js, MongoDB, Redis and Elasticsearch.
- · Developed the Referral system of Jabama.
- Contributed to migrating legacy monolith codebase to a microservices codebase.

Senior Front-End Developer

Jabama - 2019-05 / 2019-09 (4 months) - full-time

- Communicated and worked closely with the Marketing and SEO teams to add analytical tools (Google Analytics/Hotjar) to the web application.
- Worked closely with Product, UI/UX, Back-end, and QA teams to develop a redesigned version of the Product Details Page, leading to a 1.5% increase in conversion rate.
- Maintained legacy codebase and contributed to fixing critical bugs.

Open-Source Projects

GoStreestTest

github.com/arashrasoulzadeh/GoStreestTest

A tool for stress testing REST endpoints. Written in Go programming language.

Jabama/vue-carousel

github.com/jabama-co/vue-carousel

Cloned from the popular <u>vue-carousel</u> repo, with some additional features such as vertical carousel and nested carousels included.

Nuxt-dto

github.com/farnabaz/nuxt-dto

Nuxt-dto is a Nuxt.js module developed to ease the communication with REST APIs, especially when your product still is in MVP stage and breaking changes to endpoints are inevitable.

Technical Skills

Expert

ES6-ES2020, Typescript, React, Redux, Vue, Nuxtjs, Node, Express, Nestjs, Websocket, Web Workers, Jest, HTML, CSS, SCSS, MongoDB, Redis, Bootstrap, Responsive Web Design

Intermediate

Go, Elasticsearch, Nginx, RabbitMQ, Storybook, CSS-in-JS, Angular +5, Cypress, Git

Novice

Elixir, PHP, Python, Django, Nextjs, GraphQL, MySQL, Posrgresql, Angularjs, Webpack

Personal Skills

- Having Leadership Qualities.
- · Ability to work under pressure.

Amirali Heidari

+989190912275

amiraliamhh@gmail.com

in <u>linkedin://amiraliameri</u>

github://amiraliamhh

stackoverflow://amirali-ameri

EXPERIENCE

Front-End Developer

Arta Sarmayeh - 2018-12 / 2019-06 (7 months) - full-time

- Worked closely with Product, Design and Back-end teams to deliver a **pixel-perfect** and fully functional web application to help stock traders maximize their gains.
- Used React, Redux, Redux-saga, Web Workers and Service Workers to maximize the performance of the web application.
- Developed e2e and unit tests with over 90% code coverage using Jest and Cypress.

Education

Self Educated

Languages

English (Professional working proficiency)

Farsi (Native Proficiency)

Full-Stack Developer

Bitooman - 2018-01 / 2018-12 (1 year) - full-time

- Used Node, Express, Typescript, Angular, and React to develop a fully functioning cryptocurrency exchange platform.
- Developed admin panel of Bitooman which helps traders analyze crypto-market using live (websocket) cryptocurrency statistics and charts.
- Worked on internal tools for the Marketing team to assist them in acquiring more users for the platform.

Front-End Developer

IranCIP - 2017-08 / 2017-10 (3 months) - contract

 Used Angular 2 and Ionic to develop the Android application of IranCIP.